## **Bob Roudebush**

430 N. Park Ave. #412 • Indianapolis, IN 46202 Phone: 317-728-9984 • E-mail: bob@roudybob.net

## **Summary**

I'm a proven leader with 24 years of technology marketing, sales, implementation and strategy consulting experience. I bring a high-energy, creative approach to problem solving and the ability to bridge the gap between technical depth and business value. My wide range of experience, written communication skills and comfort with presenting to audiences of all sizes combined with a passion for evolving with the pace of technology innovation are my greatest assets.

## **Skills**

Enterprise IT Infrastructure Software/Hardware Public Speaking and Presentations

Cloud Computing Architecture and Implementation Enterprise Mobility and Device Management

Technical Sales and Product Marketing Technology Evangelism and Strategy

## **Professional Experience**

**Google** – I worked as part of the Google Cloud organization which includes the Google Cloud Platform public cloud infrastructure, as well as G Suite, enterprise versions of Android and Chrome OS, and application programming interfaces (APIs) for machine learning and enterprise mapping services.

Customer Engineer October 2018 – Present

As part of the rapidly growing GCP business, I worked with customers to help transform and evolve their business through the use of Google Cloud Platform. I was responsible for engaging with prospects, assessing customer requirements, preparing and presenting demonstrations of Google Cloud products and services as well as guiding customers through implementation and production deployments.

• As part of the newly formed enterprise sales team for Indiana, worked to secure the first 5 enterprise customers for Google Cloud Platform in my first year in role.

**Microsoft Corporation** – Microsoft is a worldwide leader in software, services and solutions with over 140,000 employees and \$110B in revenue annually. During my time at Microsoft, I had the benefit of serving in a variety of roles across many different aspects of the business.

Azure Cloud Solution Architect

July 2016 - October 2018

Dedicated technical architect for Microsoft's largest Azure customer worldwide. Provided technical design guidance, implementation assistance and strategy consulting for multiple customer projects. Focused on Azure compute, storage and virtual network services as part of Microsoft's laaS offerings. Highlights:

 Led technical efforts with customer for Microsoft's first "at-scale" SAP/HANA on Large Instance deployment for a ~7TB SAP BW/HANA environment which was critical to the financial reporting process for their \$32B annual revenue business.

Intune Service Engineer

July 2015 - July 2016

Led the Intune engineering team's efforts as it relates to the support of Microsoft Intune's "white glove" customers – our most visible and strategic Intune adopters. In addition to organizing the team's approach to working with these customers, I also worked directly with feature development teams to resolve technical blocker escalations from the broader Intune customer base. Highlights:

 Direct support of AON helped assist and influence their deployment of 21,000+ mobile devices managed by Intune – the largest Intune Standalone deployment worldwide. Direct support of Deloitte helped assist and influenced their deployment of 70,000+ mobile devices managed by Intune – the largest Intune Hybrid deployment worldwide.

Enterprise Mobility Technical Specialist

September 2013 - July 2015

Chosen to provide technical sales expertise for Microsoft Intune as part of Microsoft's Incubation group within Worldwide Specialist Sales. Through the efforts of our team, the product successfully graduated into mainstream selling and I transitioned into a "Blackbelt" Technical Sales capacity where I assisted with large, complex sales opportunities and directly drove consumption of services including Intune, Azure Active Directory and Azure Rights Management Services. Highlights:

- Delivered 15 deployment wins on a quota of 7 deployment wins during FY 15 and the transition of the team from a revenue-based model to one where deployment and consumption was the primary focus.
- Achieved 150% attainment on quota in my inaugural year (FY 14) with the Americas Intune Incubation sales organization and was
  part of the team that transitioned the Intune product to mainstream selling in the Microsoft sales field.

Datacenter Technology Solution Professional (TSP)

August 2011 - September 2013

Provided technical sales support for all of Microsoft's "Datacenter" products to enterprise customers in Indiana, Illinois and Wisconsin. Delivered technical briefings and lead proof of concept engagements around Windows Server, System Center and Azure Cloud Computing. Highlights:

- In first year, achieved over 126% attainment on quota and earned "TSP of the Year" award for the Midwest District while ramping up on the product set after a 7-year hiatus.
- Worked with corporate engineering teams to build IP (Intellectual Property) around monitoring and management of SQL Server
  using System Center which was highlighted in all customer-facing Datacenter TSP demos worldwide.

**Neverfail, Inc.** – Neverfail pioneered the software-based continuous availability space, eliminating end user downtime through its high availability and disaster recovery solutions for Microsoft Windows-based applications.

Vice President of Worldwide Marketing

August 2010 - August 2011

Recruited to build and run the company's new worldwide marketing organization, providing strategy and direction for the company's traditional marketing programs, analyst relations/public relations, internet-based marketing and technical product marketing.

**Bluelock**, **LLC** (now InterVision) – BlueLock, LLC was founded in 2006 and launched as a 100% virtual hosting solution company under a then unknown term, "Infrastructure-as-a-Service" (laas).

Director of Sales Engineering

April 2010 – August 2010

Recruited to build and run the company's new worldwide marketing organization, providing strategy and direction for the company's traditional marketing programs, analyst relations/public relations, internet-based marketing and technical product marketing.

**Double-Take Software (now Carbonite)** – Double-Take Software was a leading provider of workload optimization software, enabling customers to easily migrate, backup, protect and more flexibly run critical IT workloads. The company had approximately 360 employees and was publicly traded. Double-Take Software was acquired by Vision Solutions, Inc. in 2010.

Director of Product Marketing

April 2005 – April 2010

Initially recruited to rescue a struggling OEM relationship with HP's storage division, brought much-needed organizational leadership and communication skills to the mix and helped grow the partnership to \$6M in revenue annually. I was then asked to lead the product marketing and messaging efforts of the organization through multiple product launches, an initial public offering and two corporate acquisitions. My efforts directly contributed to +30% year-over-year growth to nearly \$100M in 3 years and positive press and analyst coverage of products and services.

Microsoft Corporation – Consultant / Tech Solutions Professional June 2000 – April 2005

Great Lakes Chemical (Xerox Connect) – LAN Specialist August 1997 – June 2000

Sarcom, Inc. – Systems Engineer December 1996 – August 1997

Orthopaedics Indianapolis – MIS Technician November 1995 – December 1996

**Technical Certifications** 

CISSP® - Certified Information Systems Security Professional Google Cloud Certified Cloud Architect

Microsoft Certified Professional – Multiple Disciplines Google Cloud Certified Network Engineer

Education

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

Computer Engineering